# Juliano Daniel Marcelino, M.Sc. Freelance Systems Analyst

### **Profile**

I started my career in IT infrastructure and customer support, since then adding value in almost 30 years of IT Mgmt/Gov, consulting and teaching, across worldwide companies experience. In the last years I've been increasing hard skills both in software development and technologies (Flutter, Python, JS, Docker, Arch Linux and other distros), as well in agile methodologies and lean IT. On the other hand, the main soft skills are ethics, organization, QC-Story, teamwork, communication, negotiation and flexibility. Currently I have been focusing on software development and leaving teaching aside, so now the focus is tech and code.

## **Experience**

02/2013 - ongoing O Uniasselvi Group

In postgraduate and undergraduate, taught both person and distance learning, as well as orientation of course completion work, in education, engineering, administration, system analysis correlative disciplines.

□ 09/2019 - 02/2021 SENAI/SC - Jaraguá do Sul Undergraduate and professional teaching professor, in several

chairs at the Internet Systems Technologist and other courses.

107/2015 - 04/2019 Catholic University Center Santa Catarina

Professor in person and distance learning courses in Bachelor of Information Systems, Software Engineering, Analysis and Systems Development, as Administration and Production Engineering.

■ 09/2012 - 12/2013 Anhanguera Educational Extension and postgraduate professor.

09/2011 - 02/2013 Delinea Education Technology
Content professor and technical writer.

02/2009 - 02/2012 SENAI/SC - Jaraguá do Sul

IT and Business Management Specialist, professor, content, tutor and monitor in distance learning, coordinator of the computer architecture and operating systems laboratory.

2008 - 2009 • FCJ – Cenecista College of Joinville Professor in Administration and Software Development.

2008 - 2009 © CEDB – Dom Bosco Educational Center Educator in vocational training courses in IT and Administration.

2007 - 2008 • INPG - National Postgraduate Institute
Assistant professor and educational consultant.

2007 - 2008 SoftExpert Automation

Project manager at corporate management systems and consultant in BPM tools, Project Management, BSC, SWOT, KPI, competence management, quality and strategy applications.

Consultant and project management in ERP, CRM, B2B, B2C, e/c-Commerce, VMI, JIT, forecast, kanban, and SCI.



# **Life Philosophy**

I help people (and companies) to solve problems. There is no one so expert with nothing to learn, and there no one so poor with nothing to teach.

# **Keep in touch**

juliano@jmarcelino.com.br+55 (47) 99199-4901

Jaraguá do Sul - SC - Brazil

ojmarcelino ojmarcelino

## Certifications

iii 2020 **(Section 2020)** Kanban Institute Kanban Foundation (KIKF)

2020 © CertiProf

Scrum Foundations Professional Certificate (SPFC)

2020 Cisco Networking Academy

Cisco Certified Network Instructor

## **Education**

iii 2019 **○** UniSociesc

Masters of Science in Production

Engineering, with emphasis on

Lean IT.

iii 2012 **♥** Uniasselvi MBA in Teaching to Higher Education.

■ 2008 INPG

MBA (pending diploma) in Project

Management.

2007 O Univille

Bachelor in Information Systems.

## **Languages** (CEFR standards)

pt\_PT C2 C2 C1 C1 C2
us\_EN C2 C2 C1 C1 C2
pt\_BR Native language
LIBRAS B1 Equivalent

# Juliano Daniel Marcelino, M.Sc. Analista de Sistemas Freelance

## Perfil

Iniciei minha carreira em TI na área de infraestrutura e atendimento ao usuário, e desde então venho agregando valor em quase 30 anos de experiência em IT Gov/IT Mgmt, consultoria e docência em empresas de âmbito internacional.

Nos últimos anos, venho incrementando hard skill tanto em desenvolvimento e tecnologias (Flutter, Python, JS, Linux), como em metodologias ágeis e TI enxuta (Mestrado em Lean IT e certificações Scrum e Kanban. Nas soft skills, ética, organização, MASP, trabalho em equipe, comunicação, negociação e flexibilidade.

Atualmente tenho focado em desenvolvimento e deixado a docência de lado, me voltando só para tecnologias e código.

# Experiência

02/2013 - atual

Grupo Uniasselvi

Tanto na graduação quanto pós, distancial ou presencial, lecionei e orientei inúmeros TCC e disciplinas, nas áreas de educação, engenharia, administração, análise e desenvolvimento de sistemas e outras áreas correlatas.

© 9/2019 - 02/2021 SENAI/SC - Jaraguá do Sul Graduação e formação profissional, em várias cadeiras no curso de Sistemas para Internet e outros cursos.

07/2015 - 04/2019 Centro Universitário Católica de SC Professor em cursos presenciais e distanciais nas áreas de Sistemas de Informação, Engenharia de Software, Análise e Desenvolvimento de Sistemas, Administração e Engenharia.

09/2012 - 12/2013 Anhanguera Educacional Professor de Pós Graduação e Extensão.

09/2011 - 02/2013 Delinea Tecnologias Educacionais Professor conteudista e escritor técnico.

© 2/2009 - 02/2012 SENAI/SC – Jaraguá do Sul Especialista em TI e Gestão, professor, tutor, monitor e conteudista em EaD, coordenador do laboratório de Arquitetura de Computadores e Sistemas Operacionais.

2008 - 2009 FCJ - Cenecista College of Joinville Professor de Administração e Análise e Desenvolvimento.

2008 - 2009 © CEDB - Centro Educacional Dom Bosco Educador em treinamentos nos cursos de TI e Administração.

2007 - 2008 • INPG – Instituto Nacional de Pós Graduação Professor assistente e consultor educacional.

2007 - 2008 SoftExpert Informática

Gerente de Projetos de sistemas corporativos, e consultoria em implantação de BPM, Gestão de Projetos, BSC, SWOT, KPI, gestão por competências, qualidade e planejamento estratégico.

Consultor e gerente de projetos em ERP, CRM, B2B, B2C, e/c-Commerce, VMI, JIT, forecast, kanban, e SCI.



## Filosofia de vida

Eu ajudo pessoas (e empresas) a resolver problemas. Não há ninguém tão grande que não tenha nada a aprender, e nem tão pequeno que não tenha nada a ensinar.

### Contato

juliano@jmarcelino.com.br+55 (47) 99199-4901

Jaraguá do Sul - SC - Brazil

ojmarcelino ojmarcelino

# Certificações

2020 **S** Kanban Institute Kanban Foundation (KIKF)

2020 © CertiProf
Scrum Foundations Professional
Certificate (SPFC)

2020 © Cisco Networking Academy

Cisco Certified Network Instructor

# Educação

iii 2019 **○** UniSociesc Mestrado em Engenharia de Produção com ênfase em Lean IT.

☐ 2012 Uniasselvi

MBA em Docência no Ensino

Superior.

MBA (diploma pendente) Em Gerenciamento de Projetos.

acharel em Sistemas de Informação..

## Idiomas (padrão QECR)

pt\_PT C2 C2 C1 C1 C2
us\_EN C2 C2 C1 C1 C2
pt\_BR Lingua materna
LIBRAS Equivalente ao B1